When you get there, you will understand.
The Abyss is a adventure, thriller, science
fiction film directed by James Cameron.
A civilian oil rig crew is recruited to conduct a search and rescue
effort when a nuclear submarine mysteriously sinks.
One diver soon finds himself on a spectacular odyssey 25,000 feet below the ocean's surface where he
confronts a mysterious force that has the power to change the world or destroy it.
Virgil 'Bud' Brigman, played by Ed Harris.
Lindsey Brigman, played by Mary Elizabeth Mastrantonio.
Lieutenant Hiram Coffey, played by Michael Biehn.
Catton ‘Catfish’ De Vries, played by Leo Burmester.
Alan 'Hippy' Carnes, played by Todd Graff.
Jammer Willis, played by John Bedford Lloyd.
The Abyss is a 1989 American science fiction film written and directed by James Cameron
and starring Ed Harris, Mary Elizabeth Mastrantonio, and Michael Biehn.
When an American submarine sinks in the Caribbean, a U.S.
search and recovery team works with an oil platform crew,
racing against Soviet vessels to recover the boat.
Deep in the ocean, they encounter something unexpected.
The film was released on August 9, 1989 by 20th Century Fox, receiving
generally positive reviews and grossed $90 million.
At the 62nd Academy Awards, it was nominated for four
Academy Awards, winning Best Visual Effects.
The film explores themes of sea, flying saucer, submarine, ocean, diving suit.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.